<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Econ03ge3as on econ03ge3a</title>
    <link>/econ03ge3a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Econ03ge3as on econ03ge3a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/econ03ge3a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1. Indian Economy on the Eve of Independence</title>
      <link>/econ03ge3a/indian-economy-on-the-eve-of-independence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03ge3a/indian-economy-on-the-eve-of-independence/</guid>
      <description>ReferenceNCERT Text Book Chapter 1.IntroductionA look at the state of India’s economy prior to the country’s independence and form an idea of the various considerations that shaped India’s post-independence development strategy.The structure of India’s present-day economy is not just of current making; it has its roots steeped in history, particularly in the period when India was under British rule which lasted for almost two centuries before India finally won its independence on 15 August 1947.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. A New India? </title>
      <link>/econ03ge3a/a-new-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03ge3a/a-new-india/</guid>
      <description>ReferenceAn Uncertain Glory: India and its contradictions by Jean Drèze and Amartya Sen, 2013. Chapter 1.IntroductionThe recent achievements of modern, democratic India are not inconsiderable, and have been widely recognized across the globe over the last decade or more.India’s record in pioneering democratic governance in the non-Western world is a widely acknowledged accomplishment, as is its basic success in maintaining a secular state, despite the challenges arising from its thoroughly multi-religious population and the hugely problematic history of violence around the ending days of the Raj.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Integrating Growth and Development</title>
      <link>/econ03ge3a/integrating-growth-and-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03ge3a/integrating-growth-and-development/</guid>
      <description>ReferenceAn Uncertain Glory: India and its contradictions by Jean Drèze and Amartya Sen, 2013. Chapter 2.A short history of fast growthHow long a history of fast economic growth does India have?There are many more signs of life in the Indian economy today than could be seen when political independence was granted to the ancient land in 1947, after which its straitlaced economy moved at a resiliently slow pace – about 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. The Recovery of India</title>
      <link>/econ03ge3a/the-recovery-of-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03ge3a/the-recovery-of-india/</guid>
      <description>ReferencesVisible Hand: Public Policy and Economic Growth in the Nehru EraThe Recovery of IndiaIntroductionPaper written by PB in 2007 when Indian economy was growing at around 9% (constant prices).A certain despondency induced by a sense of an allegedly “wasted past”.Some have blamed Nehru and the policies adopted under his leadership.These are serious allegations that need to be addressed.Economic growth researchers more interested in growth transitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Growth Record of Indian Economy</title>
      <link>/econ03ge3a/growth-record-of-indian-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/econ03ge3a/growth-record-of-indian-economy/</guid>
      <description>ReferenceGrowth Record of the Indian Economy, 1950-2008: A Story of Sustained Savings and Investment
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>